Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
His Majesty the Emperor.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Where is your mother?
She heard that Your Majesty was coming
so she excused herself and left.
Why, am I so intimidating
that I've scared away my own mother-in-law?
Mother always says that it's inappropriate for wives
of court officials to meet with Your Majesty.
She fears any breaches of imperial protocol.
Father also frequently advises her
not to stay for too long in the palace
or else people would start gossiping.
Where was Your Majesty before coming here?
I came here from the Chamber of Chrysanthemums.
Meizhuang makes the most delicious
lotus osmanthus cakes.
Has Your Majesty tried some?
Her lotus osmanthus cakes are sweet indeed.
But she herself is not so.
Whenever I visit her,
she almost always finds excuses
not to be close to me.
Does she still hold a grudge against me
because of how I wronged her in the past?
Your Majesty must not blame Meizhuang.
It's all my fault.
I wasn't blaming her.
What are you apologizing for?
Meizhuang wouldn't have a grudge against Your Majesty about what happened in the past.
It's all because I misspoke when talking with her.
Meizhuang and I have been good friends since childhood
and we entered the palace at the same time.
We hope to accompany Your Majesty for eternity.
Meizhuang is always thinking about
Your Majesty's well-being.
If there are too many concubines in favor,
it would surely affect Your Majesty's health.
Meizhuang expressed her worry to me
when we talked about this in the past.
Your Majesty has always cared for
me and Lingrong more than her.
So Meizhuang decided to live in the mold
of the virtuous concubines of old.
Caring for Your Majesty's health
instead of striving for Your Majesty's favor.
That's why Meizhuang has been keeping her distance.
It turns out that
Lady Vertu actually cares very deeply about me.
In that regard, I'm not as considerate as Meizhuang.
Why is that?
I cannot be a virtuous concubine.
I ...
want to spend more time with Your Majesty.
Virtuous concubines are indeed nice to have.
But they lack feminine charms,
unlike you.
Your Highness can finally rest easy
after realizing your long-cherished wish.
All the painstaking effort I've made is worth it.
I've finally secured a bright future for Wenyi.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
Don't congratulate me yet.
I'm only a Concubine for now.
Consort, Noble Consort ...
I'm going to crawl my way up.
The higher I stand, the brighter
Wenyi's prospects will be.
And the more likely she will be
arranged into a good marriage.
Your Highness might be overthinking.
Actually, as long as His Majesty adores the princess,
there is nothing to worry about.
How would you know?
His Majesty is in his prime.
He is bound to have more princes in the future.
Princesses are not highly-regarded, to begin with.
Unless they are a State Princess, born to the Empress.
But Wenyi is merely the daughter of a Concubine.
One wrong move, and Wenyi would be
arranged into a marriage alliance like Princess Zhaogui.
Your Highness has really exerted yourself for the princess.
Wenyi is my only child,
and I am her only mother.
In this vast palace,
Wenyi and I can depend only on each other.
Your Highness must not say that.
There's also Her Highness Concubine Sourire.
Consort Fleur is not reliable,
but Concubine Sourire is even worse.
People come together when there's something to gain,
and go their separate ways when there's nothing left.
If Concubine Sourire hinders my way to
becoming a Consort in the future,
I will show no mercy.
I heard that you've already granted Nian Gengyao suicide.
Yes.
Nian Gengyao would not dare to defy my order.
Now that Nian Gengyao has been taken care of,
you have one fewer problem on your mind.
As for Companion Nian ...
What do you plan to do about her?
After all, Shilan and I
have been husband and wife for years
and we share gratitude and devotion.
I feel guilty towards her for many things that happened.
As long as she creates no more trouble,
I will promote her to Noble Lady in the future
so that she can live peacefully in the palace.
You cherish the affection between you two.
But Companion Nian has a fiery temper.
I doubt she'll be able to avoid trouble.
Imperial Mother,
Lady Cao's Concubinary Ceremony is coming up soon.
I will ask her to bring Wenyi here
to pay their respects.
Good. I haven't seen Wenyi for some time.
I appreciate your rewarding of Lady Cao.
I'm not blind to Lady Cao's betrayal of her former master.
It's just that the situation required her to do so.
Only with her revelation of
Companion Nian's crimes in the harem
could I convince people's hearts and quiet their mouths.
Your plan was wise indeed.
But for someone like her,
while it is appropriate to promote her status,
she does not deserve your favor.
Who knows what she's thinking
when she shares your pillow at night?
Equally blessed with intelligence,
yet Concubine Sourire is superior to her.
Being too smart is not a good thing.
Now that Nian Gengyao has been settled,
you don't need to discuss state affairs
with Concubine Sourire.
Although Concubine Sourire behaves with propriety,
if she hears too much about the state affairs,
it might grow selfish desires in her.
Then it would be difficult to rectify the situation.
I will act within the bounds of propriety.
Even though Nian Gengyao has been eliminated,
there are still other officials who are just like him,
exploiting my favor and wielding arbitrary power.
They must be eliminated one by one.
Nian Gengyao and Longkodo
aided your accession to the throne.
Nian Gengyao was domineering
but Longkodo is growing old.
You could consider allowing him to retire
and spend his remaining years peacefully.
Imperial Mother, you have Longkodo's interests in mind,
but he himself doesn't.
I will revisit this in the future.
Besides, I didn't mention Uncle Longkodo.
Imperial Mother, why did you think of him?
It just came to mind incidentally.
It's getting late. I shall take my leave.
All right.
Be careful on your way back.
Yes.
His Majesty departs.
Bamboo.
Yes.
Do you think the Emperor ...
Is he also going to remove Longkodo
after Nian Gengyao?
His Majesty is not someone who forgets a favor.
Really?
But many people have been chattering behind closed doors
about his punishment of Nian Gengyao,
saying that the Emperor is ruthless and
unfaithful in his gratitude.
Nian Gengyao was doomed by his misconduct.
But General Longkodo is not like him.
But I have often heard
that General Longkodo has promoted
officials using his influence,
and has also formed a faction,
of his own.
Your Majesty need not worry so much about state affairs.
Restoring your health is of utmost importance.
Cao.
Sourire, you look to be in good spirits.
How couldn't I be?
It is a wonderful day for you today.
And Noble Lady Délice has moved into the
Palace of Gathering Excellence this morning.
Won't that be lively?
The Palace of Gathering Excellence
is luxuriously decorated.
We can see the importance of
Lady Délice in His Majesty's eyes.
Gūwalgiya Emin, Lady Délice's father,
made outstanding contributions
to the pacification of
State Prince Dun and Nian Gengyao.
It's no wonder that His Majesty views her favorably.
Indeed.
Are you all right? Try to stand up.
Stand up.
What's going on?
What's the matter? What happened?
- Peace and grace to Your Highness.
- Peace to Your Highness.
You may all rise.
What happened? You're all useless.
How could the princess fall over
while under your care?
What careless and lazy servants!
Tomorrow I will ask Her Majesty to
give you all a good flogging.
Check whether the princess has been injured.
I am grateful for Your Highness's help.
It was nothing.
Is Your Highness all right?
I'm fine.
The princess just fell over.
I was quick to catch her.
I don't think she was injured.
But it would be prudent to send for
the imperial doctors.
I agree with Your Highness.
Dulcet, call for the doctors.
Yes.
You all may rise.
Little Wenyi.
She is not shy with Your Highness.
She's very happy to see Your Highness.
Good girl.
Princess Wenyi likes Your Highness so much.
So lovely.
Why is Your Highness alone? Where is Auspice?
I told her to collect some snow
from on top of the bamboo leaves.
I was waiting here for her.
Your Highness's clothes are soiled.
If Your Highness doesn't mind,
you can get changed in the Palace of Pearl Jade.
All right.
Jade, go with Her Highness.
Yes.
I shall join Your Highness shortly.
It's a pity that my family has declined.
Although I am a concubine now,
I can't guarantee a good future for Wenyi.
If I could become a Consort
like Her Highness Consort Honnête,
then things would be different.
I was just saying that.
Sourire, don't take my words seriously.
[There is only one vacancy for Consort now]
I haven't.
I appreciate your ambition.
You have to plan for Wenyi's future if not for yourself.
I'm the honorary mother of the princess.
I certainly hope that she can marry a good man
which will also be an honor to me.
I thank Your Highness for your good wishes.
I can't compare with you in His Majesty's favor.
Your father has just made
great contributions to the court
and gained so much trust from His Majesty.
Your promotion to the rank of Consort
is sure to happen in countable days.
Wenyi's future may all depend on you, Sourire.
"Aide" means assistance.
His Majesty's choice of this character
for your honorary name
has profound meaning.
I know little about words.
May I trouble you to explain it to me?
What was the reason that you were
granted the rank of Concubine?
It was that Nian Gengyao had just been pacified by the court.
But in the harem, someone had to
come forward to take down Consort Fleur.
And that person was you.
So His Majesty promoted you as Concubine Aide.
That's why this name was chosen.
But unfortunately, Nian Shilan is still a Companion.
His Majesty was probably
hindered by his affection and dignity
to impose any further punishment on her.
Consort Honnête is in your palace.
I believe you need to return soon.
I shall be leaving with the princess now as well.
Your Highness must be more careful in the future.
Thank you.
Your Highness.
You're back.
Please sit.
Jinxi, take Her Highness's clothes
and have them washed.
Yes.
It's cold outside.
Come sit.
Your Highness, are your hands all right?
Let me have a look.
Yes.
Not a finger hurt.
Your Highness has always disliked Consort Fleur.
Concubine Aide was her follower in the past.
Why did Your Highness put yourself
in harm's way to save her child?
The child is innocent of her mother's actions.
Your Highness adores that child so much.
I was not blessed to bear a child.
So I can only care for the children of others.
But that child is truly so adorable.
She does seem as clever as her mother.
I only hope
that she will not learn the wiles of her mother.
That's difficult - she hears and sees them always.
If only she could be raised by a different mother,
she could be properly edified.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Peace to all the sisters in the harem.
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
(Noble Lady Délice)
You are beautiful indeed.
Come closer. Let me see you.
Yes, Your Majesty.
A pretty face and an auspicious name.
There has been so much joyful news in the harem recently.
Noble Lady Délice is beautiful,
but I can tell she's calculating from her eyes.
The more women there are in the harem,
the more calculating they become,
and the more quarrels and conflicts there are as well.
Yet women will always be found aplenty in the palace.
Take a guess.
Will His Majesty select her to serve him tonight?
That's easy.
Did you think it was going to be you or me?
You tease!
Her father made great contributions to
suppressing Nian Gengyao's rebellion.
Indeed.
She doesn't seem like the sort to be trifled with.
I quite agree.
Things are about to get exciting in the harem again.
Sourire!
Peace to Concubine Sourire.
Peace to Noble Lady Vertu.
A pleasure to meet you, Noble Lady Délice.
Before I entered the palace,
my father told me that he worked
with your father in the Censorate.
So I came to pay my respects.
I heard that your father dedicated himself
to the pacification of Nian Gengyao.
His Majesty greatly appreciates his efforts.
I'm flattered, Concubine Sourire.
I'm new to the palace.
I hope that Your Highness can enlighten me
if I breach ritual propriety.
Like you said, we are old acquaintances.
Please don't address me so formally.
Sourire, may I visit your place
if it's not too much trouble?
It's my pleasure.
I was worried that you wouldn't want to come.
Your Majesty,
Attendant Services is here.
please select a name tag.
(Noble Lady Délice)
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
What's going on outside?
I'll go find out.
Lady Délice.
Sourire, I've come to join you here.
Why didn't you let me know you were moving here?
I could have helped you arrange it.
I'm new to the palace.
But I feel close to you already.
You live alone in the Palace of Pearl Jade.
It must be lonely.
So I asked His Majesty and Her Majesty
to allow me to live with you.
But the Palace of Pearl jade is out of the way.
It cannot compare to the Palace of Gathering Excellence.
Please don't mind my coming without consulting you.
I have nobody to rely on in the palace.
There is no one I get on with at the Palace of Gathering Excellence.
I just want a peaceful life in the palace.
So I want to be your companion.
Although the Palace of Pearl Jade
is isolated, it's calm and quiet.
I'm glad that you like it.
The western chamber was once Lady Chun's residence.
Perhaps you should move into the eastern chamber.
It's also more spacious.
Thank you, Sourire.
My Lady, everything is ready in your room.
You may leave.
This chamber is much smaller than
mine in the Palace of Gathering Excellence.
But it's a good place indeed.
My Lady, you may like this chamber,
but I think it's small and isolated.
It's quite a walk from here
to the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
It's not as convenient as the Palace of Gathering Excellence.
It has a convenient location,
but ears grow in the walls with so many people.
Although the Palace of Pearl Jade is a remote place,
the distance doesn't matter as long as
His Majesty keeps it in mind.
I was just worried that this
would be unjust to you, My Lady.
Your father exhorted you repeatedly, My Lady,
that you must get ahead in the palace.
It's important to get ahead,
but it's also important not to stand out
and be the target of evil plots.
It's known to all that His Majesty likes Concubine Sourire.
I won't be overlooked if I stay by her side.
You just served His Majesty last night.
Not only did you come early today,
but also did my hair for me.
You must be tired.
I couldn't have entered the palace
without Your Majesty's grace.
Without that, I would not be able to
serve Your Majesty even if I wanted to.
The credit goes to your father in any case.
If His Majesty didn't recognize his contributions,
the word I put in for you would mean nothing.
I felt deeply regretful for missing the Selection
due to my sickness three years ago.
I thought I wouldn't miss it this year,
But I never expected that His Majesty would cancel it.
Luckily, Your Majesty's weighty words made my wish come true.
Your wish is also that of the Manchu Banners.
Take a look around the harem.
Apart from myself and Lady Fuca,
who else is from the Manchu Banners?
This is almost a realm of the Han Banners.
Before, it was Consort Fleur.
And now, Concubine Sourire.
When the Han concubines are exclusively in favor,
can we Manchu Banners have any place in the palace?
My father said the same.
They both made contributions in
pacifying Nian Gengyao's rebellion,
but why was her father promoted to the dual role of Minister of Personnel and Left Imperial Censor
while my father only became an inferior
Deputy Imperial Censor?
There are two kinds of people in this world.
One takes pleasure first and suffers later,
while the other is the opposite.
It's your choice.
I choose to suffer first and reap the rewards later.
That's good.
Some officials gain promotions and wealth
because their daughters gain favor.
Now you can also be that kind of daughter.
The best way to become a favored concubine
is to closely observe a favored concubine.
I thank Your Majesty.
Her Majesty is so kind to you, My Lady.
She considers everything for you.
That is just because
we are both from the Manchu Banners.
That's why Her Majesty treats me more generously.
Not only that, but His Majesty
is also fond of you, My Lady.
Her Majesty needs to win you over.
Choose some of the best items bestowed by Her
Majesty and give them to Concubine Sourire.
A gesture from her new guest.
Who is it?
How dare you not bow to Noble Lady Délice?
Who did I think it would be?
Isn't this Her Highness Consort Fleur?
Your Highness is forgetful
and still clings to the past glory of your family.
But you forget that
"When the tree topples, the monkeys scatter".
"When the tree topples, the monkeys scatter."
What an accurate saying.
You entered the harem on your family's contributions.
Do you think you are any different from me?
You may have high hopes for yourself.
But I am afraid you will end up just like me.
How dare a lowly Companion offend me?
You will know the consequences once I
tell Her Majesty and Concubine Sourire.
So what if you tell the Empress and Concubine Sourire?
They were both defeated at my hands.
Besides,
you are just a worthless bitch to them.
They may be enjoying a moment of satisfaction,
but there will also be a time when they fall from grace.
Let's wait and see.
My Lady, let's hurry.
The palace forbids burning joss paper.
It's a serious offense if we are discovered.
You and I are the only ones here.
I cannot get out of the palace.
Where else can I go to burn paper for my brother?
There is only you
who stayed with me even after
my fall from favor brought you down.
I have served you since I was very young, My Lady.
I would do anything for you.
I'd better go outside and watch, My Lady.
You offended Lady Délice today
and there might be trouble.
Why would I be afraid of her?
I'm fine if she wants to come,
or if His Majesty wants to kill me.
Right now,
living is no different from dying to me.
Don't be so sad, My Lady.
We still have many days ahead of us.
But His Majesty ...
He killed my brother, Nian Fu, and Nian Xing.
He no longer favors me.
What else do I have to live for?
This life ...
will be spent waiting to die here.
His Majesty was so merciless ...
All because of that bitch Zhen Huan.
Even if I die,
I still won't let her go.
Where is Su Xi?
Following your orders, Su Xi went on an errand.
His Majesty the Emperor.
Peace to Your Majesty.
What's wrong?
You aren't happy?
I've never been so insulted since
I came out of my mother's womb.
Please forgive me for my discourtesy.
What happened exactly?
If you don't tell me, how am I supposed to
know your grievances?
Your Majesty, I am new in the palace,
I don't know if order in the palace is determined by rank?
Of course.
If someone of lower rank offends their superiors,
shouldn't they be punished according to the rules?
They should.
Look at you.
You've said so much yet still haven't gotten to the point.
How am I supposed to bring you justice?
I encountered Companion Nian in the palace.
But she regarded me as nothing
and scoffed that I entered the palace
by courtesy of my family's merits.
She said that regardless of my high hopes,
I will end up like her.
Companion Nian has a poor temper.
Just ignore her.
Look at you.
Your makeup has run and your hair is crooked
due to your crying.
It doesn't look pretty anymore.
Your Majesty is being biased.
You just said that concubines must respect their superiors, yet you make an exception for Companion Nian.
She has the nerve to treat me like this now.
What if ...
Who knows if she will try to end my life one day?
Fine.
I would be very sad if you were to get killed.
Go wash your face,
and I will handle this matter.
Really?
Then I can put my mind at ease.
Su Peisheng.
Your Majesty.
Did what Lady Délice say really happen?
Your Majesty,
Lady Délice's words are truthful.
But Companion Nian might have had her reasons.
Today marks three weeks
since Nian Gengyao's death.
It's no wonder that she was in a bad mood.
I heard that Lady Délice was sad last night.
Ladies get moody sometimes.
Lady Délice is not an unreasonable person.
There must be a reason she was upset.
She was just annoyed by Companion Nian.
And Companion Nian is really something.
She's fallen to her current status,
but she still oversteps the bounds.
Companion Nian has offended her superiors repeatedly,
and Your Majesty has always been tolerant.
But her impertinence has only gotten worse.
She has squandered Your Majesty’s grace.
So what do you suggest?
Nian Gengyao is dead.
Your Majesty has set aside the
law to spare Companion Nian's life.
However, since Companion Nian does not repent,
Your Majesty should punish Companion Nian severely.
Execute her
to calm the anger of the harem.
Here!
You're very smart.
And also cruel.
Since you think Concubine Aide is ungrateful,
repeatedly suggesting to kill her old master,
then I think
it is unwise to keep this kind of person around.
In fact, I also know
Shilan is not bad by nature.
Many things
happened because Concubine Aide
secretly gave her counsel.
Fortunately, Concubine Aide doesn’t have a prominent family.
Nor is she in high favor.
Otherwise, such a cunning and poisonous woman
would have been removed long ago.
But Wenyi is young and can't be without her birth mother.
There are many women in the palace without children.
I think Consort Estime and Consort Honnête would do well.
They both love children.
They might even do better than her birth mother.
My Lady, wake up.
I have reheated the herbal sleep aids
prescribed by the imperial doctors.
Drink some so you will feel better when you sleep.
Your Highness.
What’s wrong?
I have been watching for the past few days
and it seems like someone is spying on us outside.
Did you see them clearly?
Yes. Twice, I couldn't get a good look.
But another two times I saw him clearly.
He pretends to be cleaning in Long Street.
But actually, he hides under the wall
and eavesdrops in the corner.
Did you see who it was, or which palace he's from?
It's one of Companion Nian's eunuchs,
named Su Xi.
After His Majesty punished Zhou Ninghai,
Su Xi replaced him.
Once I even saw him carrying some kind of flint,
seemingly harboring malicious intentions.
But because the palace is tightly guarded,
he hasn’t been able to do anything yet.
Does Your Highness want me to seize him,
and bring him to His Majesty?
Ignore him.
Be careful of what he does secretly.
Don’t “beat the grass and frighten away the snake”.
Yes, Your Highness. I will take my leave.
The sun is so nice today.
Go invite Meizhuang to play Go with me.
Yes.
But Her Majesty the Empress
invited Lady Délice to the opera house.
Do you wish to join them, My Lady?
I heard that Lady An is going too.
Right now, they're playing the lead role.
I'm not going to take part in it.
Go invite Meizhuang.
Certainly.
I brought you all here today
because it's almost the [lunar] New Year.
I believe that everyone misses home.
Also, I wanted to take this chance
to speak with everyone freely,
unlike in the Palace of Great Benevolence.
We are grateful for Your Majesty's benevolence.
All right. Let's be seated to enjoy the show.
I thank Your Majesty.
We're so fortunate to have Your Majesty.
Otherwise, as it comes to the New Year,
I would feel empty somehow.
Not to mention the disrespectful behavior I suffered.
In my heart ...
It's no longer like at home in the palace.
It's only natural that you would feel somewhat aggrieved.
But we are all sisters.
So we make allowances for each other.
Your Majesty’s comfort and guidance
makes my heart much warmer.
Now, isn't Lady Délice a smooth talker?
You've spoken the contents of our very hearts.
In comparison, the rest of us sound
clumsy and ineloquent.
Listening to you now, it sounds just like
a conversation with my own family.
It puts me at ease.
As long as Your Majesty doesn't mind my verbosity.
I have two sisters born of a secondary wife.
I don't have anything to talk to them about.
But when I'm around Your Majesty,
my heart is filled with things to say.
I misspoke.
I beg Your Majesty's forgiveness.
Your Majesty, Lady Délice did not mean to.
It’s fine. Let’s watch the show.
I thank Your Majesty.
Please forgive me, Your Majesty.
I have already said
concubines in the harem are all sisters.
There's no need to be small-minded.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty for your generosity.
All of you may leave.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty must be tired.
You should get some rest.
Talking with Lady Délice is tiring indeed.
But you are different. You are smart.
I'm flattered, Your Majesty.
I just hope
Your Majesty isn’t angry at Lady Délice.
Lady Délice is foolish but beautiful indeed.
We need this kind of woman in the harem.
Serving His Majesty doesn’t require intelligence.
Only a pretty face.
This kind of woman will take a portion of
His Majesty's favor, but never exclusively.
That's why I like you.
You are not the most beautiful,
but you are smart, well-behaved, and loyal to me.
I received Your Majesty's grace despite my slow-wits.
I must be loyal and devoted.
Loyalty is not proven with words.
"Only the passage of days reveals a person's heart".
I won't forget what you've done for me.
I am just a humble Noble Lady without an honorary title.
Unlike Lady Délice, who gained such an
exalted position upon entering the palace.
So what of a humble origin?
I was born of a secondary wife.
So I resent it the most when people say
"born of a secondary wife".
But I've realized that being born
of a secondary wife doesn't matter.
I am still the Empress, the Mother of All Under Heaven.
At least your father is the
Assistant Magistrate of Songyang Village.
If you really think your family is humble,
why don’t you use your favor to turn things around
and rise above the others?
I thank Your Majesty for your advice.
I will always remember it.
No no! Let me take that back.
You can't play like that!
All right. It's obvious I'm going to lose.
I give up.
Come on, you can't take back a move when you regret it.
Don't be so petty.
Let’s play one more round.
I feel so annoyed.
Even if we play ten more games, I'll still lose them all.
I know what you're annoyed about.
Unfortunately, the time has not yet come.
After all, she was in favor for so many years.
Ending her once and for all won't be easy.
How would you know the hatred in my heart?
I hate her even more than you do.
What I lost from my belly
was my own flesh and blood.
Is Lady Délice back?
Your Highness has forgotten, after watching the show,
Lady Délice went to have dinner in Consort Estime's palace.
The snow outside has just melted.
She might have trouble finding her way back.
Light a few more lanterns by the entrance to her chamber.
Su Xi is here.
He slipped into Lady Délice's chamber.
After all this time,
he finally got an opportunity to make this move.
Whether he is able to or not depends on Your Highness.
If I don’t let him,
how will he reassure his master that he finished the job?
What riddle are you playing at?
Go out and wait for him.
Once the fire has started, seize him.
Yes.
Meizhuang,
do you want to see how Nian Shilan digs her own grave?
Follow me.
Lady Délice's chamber is connected to mine.
If a fire spreads from there,
there's no way I would be able to escape.
This is the osmanthus oil for combing your hair.
Why are you pouring it out?
Don't make a sound.
Don't keep me in the dark about your plan!
Nian Shilan sent her servant to burn me to death.
I don’t want to hurt anyone,
but I won't let anyone hurt me either.
So you are going to give her a hand.
It's "presenting Buddha with borrowed flowers".
Well, if we are going to act out a play,
we'll need a full scene.
I don't want her to have any chance of surviving this.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.